Douglas C. Beasley

I am a resourceful and passionate software engineer of 16 years. I have experience writing both public and internal service oriented applications and finding creative solutions to complex problems. The majority of my experience is with Java and associated frameworks like Spring. I've had the opportunity to work closely with data engineering and data science teams, and have a working knowledge of data pipelines, machine learning and big data. I have a specific interest in high-performance, real-time applications and have authored production applications using functional reactive programming with Scala, Akka and Reactor.

Professional Experience

November 2016 - Present

Principal Software Engineer at Red Ventures

- Architected the Bedrock micro-sevice platform to service the ThePointsGuy mobile application, Bankrate authenticated experience and other Red Ventures properties
- Reauthored the reward calculation algorithm reducing cyclomatic complexity from 214 to 10
- Containerized legacy applications, modernized test suites and applied CI/CD systems for ECS deployments
- Authored the functional test suite with fixture generation using Spring Shell to support a comprehensive testing framework for QA
- Worked closely with data engineering and data science teams to provide meaningful insights for machine learning and business intelligence
- Advising on platform architecture, software implementations and SDLC

April 2014 - November 2016

Vice President of Engineering at Causecast

- Managing the Engineering, Product and QA functional areas
- Authored the Donation Engine with Groovy and Grails which is responsible for payment processing and funds disbursement of over \$3M dollars annually
- Developed a functional donation receipt processing service with Akka and Scala, tested scalability to 100 cluster nodes.
- Developed a hybrid sprint planning model to accommodate lean product specifications
- Instituted a formal code review process
- Member of the Product Council, involved in roadmap and product planning
- Supported the Client Impact Platform with PHP and the Symfony2 framework

March 2013 - April 2014

Software Engineer/Co-Founder at Nestivity

- Co-Creator of the Nestivity product platform.
- Utilizes the OAuth1 standard for pure social (Twitter) authentication
- MongoDB persistence with Spring Data
- Hazelcast for caching and inter-node communication
- Sole author of the Muncher platform
- Muncher is responsible for handling and processing a syndicated Twitter firehose in conjunction with the Twitter public API. Currently storing 25K tweets a day
- Hazelcast for internode and interprocess communication allowing for long polling, data deduplication, and Nestivity platform synchronization.
- Implemented an automated build and test workflow with Maven, Jetty and Jenkins.

June 2012 - March 2013

Senior Software Engineer at Passenger

- Completed work on the first customer release of the Android mobile offering, supporting communication with the existing platform API.
- Brought expertise in re-architecting the current platform.
- Collaborated with development team members on the

- design and implementation to overhaul the current platform.
- Supported existing maintenance efforts with the current platform.

2003 - 2012

Senior Software Engineer at Skyworks

- Developed and maintained software applications such as the MoveMeter, Repair Parts Database, and Utilization applications; that were used by internal manufacturing and engineering departments.
- Converted source code control from MS Visual SourceSafe to CVS.
- Optimized the existing Engineering Database to achieve a 25% increase in capacity, and implemented automated data loading and monitoring.
- Developed and implemented multiple award winning applications such as the Equipment Management Control Panel, which was instrumental in the efforts of a factorywide tooling conversion; as well as the Problem Lot Disposition system, which played a key role in identifying, containing, and correcting issues on the production floor.
- Administered 8i, 9i and 11g Oracle database instances housing approximately 40 schemas. Successfully migrated existing 8i and 9i instances to a 2 node 11g Oracle RAC environment.
- Effectively transferred existing Unix/Linux systems to a new hardware and operating environment. The environment was constructed to maintain high availability by using various clustering and virtualization technologies. Linux Virtual Server and RedHat Cluster Suit were introduced to the native Apache and Tomcat solutions for clustering and load balancing.

Languages

- Java, Scala, Groovy
- Javascript TypeScript

Frameworks

- Spring, Spring Boot
- Akka
- Angular

Datastores

- Postgres, MySQL, Oracle
- MongoDB, DocumentDB
- Redis
- Elastic Search
- Kinesis, Kafka
- Neo4J

Cloud and Platform

- AWS
- GCP
- Terraform

Education, Training, & Awards

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science 2007

California Lutheran University, Thousand Oaks, CA

Award for Exceptional Performance 2010

Received the award for Exceptional Performance for the development of the Equipment Management Application. The application was critical in coordinating the effort of a 4 to 6 inch substrate conversion on the factory floor. The application also provided enhanced user control of equipment configuration in the manufacturing execution system(MES). This application was mentioned in the July 2010 issue of Compound Semiconductor, Back to GaAs Roots, pg. 30.

Award for Exceptional Performance 2004

Received the award for Exceptional Performance for the development of the Problem Lot Disposition System. The Problem Lot Disposition system is currently used in all front end manufacturing in plants including Newbury Park CA, Woburn MA and Mexicali Mexico.

Learning Tree International

Developing Enterprise Java Applications with Spring and Hibernate 9/24/2010

Application Development and Tuning for Oracle Database 5/27/2005

Backup, Recovery and Server Tuning for Oracle Databases 6/25/2004

Areas of Interest

- Robotics
- Hockey
- Scuba Diving

Contact

19725 Crystal Hills Dr. Porter Ranch, CA 91326 phone: 805.341.0832

email: beasley.doug@gmail.com

github: http://github.com/dougbeasley linkedin:

http://linkedin.com/in/douglascbeasley

Download this as a pdf (generated using node-html-pdf)
This was generated using node-html-pdf, and is rather static.
Please check out the online version where possible. <u>Url here.</u>
Last Published Friday, May 3, 2019, Portfolio upon request.